Yonatan Ben Knaan

A product designer with 15+ years of experience in leading design initiatives across agencies, startups, & companies. Doing it by leading teams & hands-on. Specializing in problem solving, backlog management, UX research, design systems & agile methods. Passionate about simplifying complexity & user-centric digital products.

Experience

2019-Present, Head of Design: Pepperi

Platform as a Service for B2B Wholesale Commerce

At Pepperi, I combine both leadership and execution abilities.

- Boost Buyer role adoption, driving B2B eCommerce growth by 40% annually.
- Streamlined design implementation (25% faster) and goal achievement (30% higher).

Enhance marketing site design to improve Bounce Rate (57% to 32%), Average Session Duration (2<min to 4>min) and Conversion Rate (1.5% to 5%).

- Enhanced and simplifid complex B2B UX to meet 'B2C-like' standards.
- Led the adoption of design thinking and proper processes, and built tools to support it.

Conduct user research and develop design strategies to streamline new product development and increase efficiency.

- Manage backlogs, coordinate with teams, clarifying goals and tracking KPIs.
- Develop a design system that increases development speed and ensures UI consistency, supporting key product features.
- Create a brand guide, strengthening brand awareness and improve sales efforts.
- Supported multiple additional teams: PS, Native Apps, Marketing, and Sales.

2015-18, Head of Design: bit.dev

B2D code management SaaS

Led brand and product design, helping devs build UI faster by reusing code components.

Conducted user research and collaborated with product and engineering teams, creating a UX adopted by thousands globally.

Transformed the product from CoCycles to Marvin, and finally to Bit, significantly enhancing its functionality and increasing user adoption.

Delivered a UX that supports thousands of developers globally, streamlining their workflows.

2009-15, Partner & Manager: Matnas Interactive

Design agency, UX/UI and product ideation.

As a partner at Matnas I strategized for growth, sought new business opportunities, and maintained supplier relationships. Supervised daily ops and managed numerous design projects simultaneously, achieving first-in-class results and high client satisfaction.

Led and mentored a team, fostering a creative and productive environment; many team members are now leading designers.

Managed 100K+ accounts, overseeing business operations; preparing and issuing quotes, and maintaining detailed budgeting processes.

Implemented quality control and stayed updated with industry trends, enhancing team performance and project success.

2018-19, Freelance

- UX Research → Avodata, a project for the JDC & the Ministry of Labor
- UX/UI Steering Committee & Lecturer → Musrara
- | Product & Brand Designer → Watchful
- | Product & Brand Designer → ColoredCoins

Info

Residence: Tel Aviv, IL
Status: Married, 1 kid, 1 dog
Phone: +972-50-785-5149
Mail: me@yonatankof.com

Highlights

Proven record in managing and launching complex systems

- | Experienced design team manager
- | Proficient in UX research
- Results-focused and efficient delivery
- | Digital craftsman and documenter
- People's person and coacher
- Designer that codes 🦄

Portfolio

| yonatankof.com/links/proj

Skills

Tools

Notion, Jira, Storybook, Whimsical, Figma/Sketch, Abstract/Branches

Methods

Design Thinking, Agile, UX Research, Design Systems, Product Design, Coaching method

Dev

HTML, CSS/SCSS, JavaScript, Bash, Git. Vue. Nuxt. Netlify

Education

2005-2009

Visual Communication @ Shenkar

1998-2000

Architecture engineering @ The Technological College of Beer-Sheva